Patrick A. Levell

email <u>patrick.a.levell@gmail.com</u> • web <u>levell.tech</u>

Profile

Results-driven Systems Analyst / Developer, Business Analyst, and Bitcoin enthusiast with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

Computer Skills

System Software

- Oracle EnterpriseOne, JD Edwards OneWorld Xe
- Windows XP/2008
- MS IIS/SharePoint
- Ubuntu Linux
- Apple OS X, iOS
- Apache

Applications

- MS Office (Outlook, Word, Excel, Access, Visio, PowerPoint)
- MS Publisher
- BFGminer / Cgminer, bitcoind, bitcoin-qt
- Wordpress

Development Tools

- SQL Server 2005/2008 (SSAS, SSIS, SSRS)
- · MySQL, SQLite
- Visual Studio, Visual Basic, VB.Net
- PyCharm
- Rational Rose UML

Professional Experience

Cryptographic System Administrator

- Procuring, installing, monitoring, and maintaining advanced cryptocurrency mining hardware & software on muliple platforms
- Researching and analyzing blockchain and mining pool performance
- · Evaluating Bitcoin trading software

Freelance Programmer / Webmaster / Database Administrator

- Mentoring bloggers, entrepreneurs, and Bitcoin startups in building and maintaining their online presence
- Performing as technical liason for clients with advertisers
- Administering customer databases
- · Migrating web-sites to new servers

Programmer / Analyst

- Working closely with executives, consultants, customers, suppliers, and end-users to define and refine requirements for Raymond's IT infrastructure
- Developing, designing, implementing, testing and maintaining the *iWarehouse™ Fleet Optimization System*, Raymond's first commercial software offering
- Supervising consultants and junior programmers working on a variety of projects
- Monitoring and troubleshoot issues in JDEdwards, data warehouse, and iWarehouse
- Developing strategy for streamlining operations by integrating business processes
- Using JDEdwards EnterpriseOne ERP forms and reports in combination with VB.Net and SQL Reporting Services in delivering optimized business solutions for National Accounts, Sales & Marketing, Warranty Services, and the Raymond dealer network

Computer Systems Analyst / Developer

- Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports in JDEdwards OneWorld ERP/MRP for Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems
- Developing specialized reports & applications with JDEdwards, SQL queries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server
- Working closely with end users in defining and "fine tuning" requirements & creating documentation
- Training and supporting JD Edwards users in Finance, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory modules

Employers

All Things Bitcoin	London, Ontario	2012 to Present
The Raymond Corporation	Greene, New York	2007 to 2012
NUCOR Vulcraft – Florence	Florence, South Carolina	1997 to 2007

Education

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems DeVry University, Chicago, Illinois Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)

Cryptocurrency Project Highlights

- Owned & operated a Bitcoin mining farm, starting with two (2) FPGA miners, epanded to six (6) first-generation ASIC miners and a second-generation ASIC miner
- · First-ever web-scraper to collect account information from GBBG|BitBillions web-site

Integrated ERP Project Highlights

Custom applications with components in multiple environments, including Oracle EnterpriseOne, JD Edwards OneWorld Xe, and SQL Server, as follows:

- iWarehouse Gateway—a web application for fleet management and optimization; modules include the following:
 - iImpact impact monitoring (asset protection)
 - iMetrics vehicle and operator utilization
 - iVerify operator checklist monitoring
 - iBattery battery utilization
- Capital Appropriations Request an intranet application to automate the capital appropriations request process, replacing the paper-based process

Exclusively ERP Project Highlights

Custom extensions or modifications on JD Edwards OneWorld Xe include the following:

- Job Master Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards, summarizing customer account and project information in credit, sales, finance, engineering, and manufacturing systems, improving documentation and communication between departments; Created a user manual and 25minute training video for this application using Snaglt, MS Publisher, and MS PowerPoint
- Production Scheduler fixed sales, purchasing, manufacturing, delivery date issues; linked to
 Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Input; resulting in fewer problems between Sales and Drafting
 Completed, Not Shipped (CNS) the Finished Goods report every nut & bolt in the plant is
 processed by this custom JD Edwards report—a critical piece of Vulcraft's month-end closing
 procedures; the Controller was using five other reports to get this information until CNS was
 fixed; month-end closing time was reduced by at least 20%; this report became an integral
 part of testing system changes in JD Edwards
- Material Resource Planning (MRP) troubleshooting, modifying, and performance-enhancing
 on this suite of batch applications, to reconcile sales, purchasing, manufacturing, and shipping dates, and reduce execution time & system resource requirements, as this is a resource
 hog
- The "Havens" Report a custom management report in JD Edwards, providing in-depth credit
 analysis of large and/or problematic customer accounts, with two sections—one for the customer, and one for top-level management
- 180-Day Weighted Average a custom financial report in JD Edwards for calculating customer credit scores, based on their last six months of credit history
- Over 40 Days a custom financial report in JD Edwards for identifying overdue accounts
- Deck Inventory a custom JD Edwards financial (MRP) report for the Controller and Purchasing Agent, detailing current and projected raw material requirements
- Fab Schedule the weekly production schedule from which most office activity stems; two
 specialized versions of this report created for Drafting and Shop Order; ties in to Manufacturing, Customer Service, Job Master, Drafting, and Shop Order Inquiry screens
- *Drafting Inquiry* added additional fields for tracking approval drawings, and signaling Production Scheduler whether drawings are in-process, out for approval, or back from approval;

- linked to the Job Master Inquiry and Shop Order Inquiry screens; resulting in providing Production Scheduler with up-to-the minute information for scheduling purposes
- Shop Order Inquiry added additional fields for tracking bills of materials (aka. shop orders)
 through the engineering design program (outside of JD Edwards); linked to Job Master Inquiry
 and Drafting Inquiry screens; resulting in much improved traceability and fewer interruptions
 in Data Entry from Drafting and Shop Order, asking for information
- Shipping Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards combining bill of lading, sales, and shipping data for much improved reachability
- Daily Shipments a key custom JDE financial report used for invoicing, reported tons & dollars
- SO SF Compare a custom JDE application for comparing what was sold to what was built & shipped; used primarily on large jobs to show the dollar amount left to be invoiced
- Re-price Program a custom JDE application for re-pricing jobs, typically used when design requirements change

Custom Application Highlights

Custom development using MS Excel/Access/. Net include the following:

- Internal Audit Manager a custom MS Access database application for managing internal audits of quality and environmental management systems; generates checklists, audit questions, and audit reports
- Inventory Tracking System a custom MS Excel spreadsheet application to analyze supplier promised & actual delivery dates using data from inventory and cost of quality spreadsheets; results delivered using charts, graphs, and pivot tables
- NUVU BoM Transfer a stand-alone application using VB.Net & SQL queries to transfer XML data from NUVU bills of materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design program, written in FORTRAN, and still thinks it is running on punch cards; complete with installer and auto-update feature for local and satellite sales offices
- Shipping Route-out Prototype this was a tool to move the current delivery dispatches ("route-out") procedures from paper-based to electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards
- *NUVU Installer* a collection of shell scripts, HTML, and VB.Net programs to install NUVU on AutoCAD workstations, including network security and administrative shares. All the users had to do to install NUVU was click on a single web-link
- Joist Input Program a front-end to the engineering design program, written in VB5 utilizing a SQL Server database instead of the old flat-files; object model created using Rational Rose; prototyping done in MS Access

Special Projects

- Recovered stolen Internet domain name for a Colorado-based real estate brokerage firm; the investigation tracked the domain records down in Australia, and the owner in Spain; assistance was obtained from the International Trade Administration at the US Department of Commerce
- Served as Senior Lead Internal Auditor for six years. Led the team to make the transition from ISO 9001:1994 to ISO 9001:2000, which included leading the team that re-wrote the quality manual, and moving the quality manual from paper-based to an interactive on-line system, using MS Internet Information Server (IIS), SharePoint, and FrontPage.
- Routinely served as corporate liaison with outside auditors of both our quality and environmental management systems.